Tester

Core Skill:

Manual Testing

Industry Verticals:

Banking Payments Technology Mobility

Programming Languages:

Visual Basic

Java Ruby

JavaScript

Databases:

Oracle

PostgreSQL

Tools & Techniques:

Agile

Postman

Newman

Jira

Mantis

Power BI

Saleforce

Summary:

I have 17 years of experience in the software industry working as a Tester, Business Analyst and Implementer. I declare myself as a hard-working, proactive, educated person, with a lot of autonomy and always trying to grow my skills. Fanatic of the Software Development Life Cycle and always with quality in my actions and activities.

Qualifications:

Educational Background:

Specialist in Software Engineering , Pontifician's Javeriana University , 2020 System Engineer , Simon Bolivar University , 2006

Certifications:

Salesforce Associate Certification , Salesforce , In Progress ISTQB Foundation , ISQi , 2023
Data Science , Occidental Autonomy University , 2022
CMMI Software Quality , ICESI University , 2018
Scrum Master , Certiprof , 2016

Spoken Languages:

Spanish, Native English, B1+

Soft Skills:

Responsability Client Relationship Autonomy Adaptability

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Industry sector: E-commerce

Tester Senior Technician

2023-12-11 - Currently

| Dro | ioct | doed | criptio | ne. |
|-----|------|------|----------|-----|
| PIU | iect | uest | ar ibtic | ms: |

Custom development in E-commerce application.

Responsibilities:

• Static testing of user stories to improve the quality of acceptance criteria. • Test case design based on the acceptance criteria of user stories. • Documenting issues and tracking the resolution of any bugs found. • Manual testing of APIs to ensure that they function according to the requested settings and documentation. • User interface testing to the E-commerce. • Regression testing of new and updated functionalities by the development team. • Active participation in all agile ceremonies.

Programming Languages:

JavaScript

Tools & Techniques:

Agile, Miro, Confluence,
BazaarVoice, SauceLabs,
Xcode Simulator, ServiceNow

Testing:

JIRA, TestRail, Manual Testing

Industry sector: Banking

Tester Senior Technician

2023-01-20 - 2023-11-30

Project descriptions:

Custom development in Salesforce for customer

Responsibilities:

• Static testing of user stories to improve the quality of acceptance criteria. • Test case design based on

| processes from opening to | the acceptance criteria of user stories. • | | |
|---------------------------|--|-------------|--|
| closing business cases. | Documenting issues and tracking the resolution of | | |
| | any bugs found. • Manual testing of APIs to ensure | | |
| | that they function according to the requested settings | | |
| | and documentation. • User interface testing for | | |
| | cases, accounts, and customers in Salesforce, as | | |
| | well as configuration. • Regression testing of new | | |
| | and updated functionalities by the development | | |
| | team. • Active participation in all agile ceremonies. | | |
| | | | |
| Programming Languages: | Tools & Techniques: | Testing: | |
| SQL | Salesforce | JIRA, Xray, | |
| | | Postman | |

Industry sector: Banking

Tester Senior Technician

| 2022-09-30 - 2023-01-15 | | | | | |
|--|--|------------------------|--|--|--|
| Project descriptions: | Responsibilities: | | | | |
| Development and customization of payment APIs for electronic businesses. | • Static testing of user stories to improve the quality of acceptance criteria. • Test case design based on the acceptance criteria of user stories. • Documenting issues and tracking the resolution of any bugs found. • Manual testing of APIs to ensure that they function according to the requested settings and documentation. • Regression testing of new and updated functionalities by the development team. • Active participation in all agile ceremonies. | | | | |
| Programming Languages: | Tools & Techniques: | Testing: | | | |
| Ruby, SQL | Postman | SQL Developer, JIRA | | | |

Industry sector: Human Resources

Tester Senior Technician

2022-08-01 - 2022-09-30

Project descriptions:

Development of platforms that allow managing the information and benefits of Endava employees.

Responsibilities:

• Test planning activities for the team. • Monitoring test executions and supporting the team as an improvement of the quality process. • Static testing of user stories to improve the quality of acceptance criteria. • Test case design based on the acceptance criteria of user stories. • Documenting issues and tracking the resolution of any bugs found. • User interface testing for cases, accounts, and customers in Salesforce, as well as configuration. • Manual testing of Endpoints to ensure that they function according to the acceptance criteria. • Regression testing of new and updated functionalities by the development team. • Leading and mentoring of other QA members. • Active participation in all agile ceremonies.

Programming Languages:

Java, Go, SQL

Tools & Techniques:

Postman, Sql developer

Testing:

JIRA, Zephyr Scale

Industry sector: Software Factory

QC Analyst Semi Senior

2021-08-18 - 2022-08-01

Project descriptions:

Manual API testing for a Travel

Responsibilities:

Technical analysis and static testing of user stories

| Programming Languages: JavaScript, SQL | Tools & Techniques: Postman, Newman, Swagger, Sql developer, Oracle | Testing : JIRA | |
|--|--|--------------------------|--|
| & Mobility project | to improve the quality of acceptance criteria. • Test case design based on the acceptance criteria of user stories. • Endpoint's Test Execution (Manual and Automated). • Documenting issues and tracking the resolution of any bugs found. • Support the Business Analyst team in defining and refining the acceptance criteria of user stories. • Regression testing of new and updated functionalities by the development team. • Active participation in all agile ceremonies. | | |